<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Indrajith Indraprastham</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Indrajith Indraprastham</description>
    <image>
      <title>Indrajith Indraprastham</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/dp.jpg</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dp.jpg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.125.5</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 21:56:55 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Recursive Queries in PostgreSQL for Hierarchical Data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/recursive-queries-in-postgresql-for-hierarchial-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 21:56:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/recursive-queries-in-postgresql-for-hierarchial-data/</guid>
      <description>Recursive queries are typically used to deal with hierarchical or tree-structured data. A common example is when you have a manager &amp;gt; employee relation in a table and you have to construct the organization tree under a manager or find all N level managers of an employee. Strictly speaking, this process is iteration not recursion, but RECURSIVE is the terminology chosen by the SQL standards committee.
PostgreSQL CTE: Common Table Expression From the docs:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On habits and behavior change</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-habits-and-behavior-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 23:17:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-habits-and-behavior-change/</guid>
      <description>Happiness is the state between one desire being fulfilled and new desire forming. Suffering is the state between craving a change in state and achieving it.
The Compounding Power of Atomic Habits The effects of small habits compound over time. If you can get 1% better each day, by the end of the year you&amp;rsquo;d have become 37 times better. Conversely with bad habits, if you had have become 1% worse every day for one year you&amp;rsquo;ll decline nearly down to zero.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to develop a Computerized Adaptive Test (CAT)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/computerized-adaptive-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 16:05:28 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/computerized-adaptive-test/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I’ll share the step by step process we used at AirCTO to create computerized adaptive tests.
At AirCTO we use adaptive tests to measure the ability of the candidate in different domains (Python, Front end development, Docker etc,.).
Back to basics: What is computerized adaptive test? Computerized adaptive testing (CAT)) is a form of computer-based test that adapts to the examinee&amp;rsquo;s ability level. For this reason, it has also been called tailored testing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Approach to Classify Music Based on Genre</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/machine-learning-aproach-to-classify-music-based-on-genre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 11:58:29 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/machine-learning-aproach-to-classify-music-based-on-genre/</guid>
      <description>Music Genre Classifier Demo Music is categorized into subjective categories called genres. With the growth of the internet and multimedia, systems applications that deal with the musical databases gained importance and demand for Music Information Retrieval (MIR) applications increased.
Musical genres have no strict definitions and boundaries as they arise through a complex interaction between the public, marketing, historical, and cultural factors. We are going to create an application that accepts a music file and classify it in to genres.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Music Visualizer in C Using OpenGL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/music-visualizer-in-c-using-opengl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 21:01:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/music-visualizer-in-c-using-opengl/</guid>
      <description>For the given input audio file (.wav) the program will give the real time audio spectrum by performing Fast Fourier Transform (FFT) on the audio samples and plot the graph using OpenGL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jumble Words solver using Python</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/jumbled-words-solver-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 18:54:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/jumbled-words-solver-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Python CTI program that gives all the possible match for the given word.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
